

📕 (+254) 725 686 201 | 💌 ericmosesngigi@gmail.com | 🧥 ericngigi.netlify.app | 🖸 erikngigi | 🛅 ericngigi-dev | 📭 erikngigi

## Summary \_\_\_\_\_

Experienced Linux System Engineer with 2 years of experience managing and maintaining Linux servers in high-availability environments. Skilled in scripting, automation, and troubleshooting. Strong track record of improving system performance, increasing uptime, and reducing downtime.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Fiverr** Freelance, Online

LINUX SYSTEM ENGINEER September 2021 - Present

- Designed and implemented automation using Ansible and Puppet, resulting in a 50% reduction in manual tasks.
- · Implemented Docker and Kubernetes for containerization, resulting in improved application performance and scalability.
- Reduced manual effort by 20% through the scripting of routine tasks using Bash.
- · Managed, configured and installed new firmware on new/existing firewalls/routers, managed switches, wireless access points and load balancers.
- Worked with developers in development of the database schema design using the Entity-relationship model as per user requirements.
- Performed Database Performance Analysis and Tuning using Database Engine Tuning Advisor, SQL Server Profiler and SQL Server Extended
- · Setup High-Availability as part Disaster Recovery Strategy for the SQL server 2012 databases (Failover Clustering, Database Mirroring, Log Shipping and Replication) achieving 99.99% uptime.
- · Achieved 99.9% server uptime in a cloud-based environment, resulting in increased system availability.

**SysCraft Limited** Nairobi, Kenya

DOCUMENT PREPARATION

November 2022 - February 2023

- Carefully handled private documents by sorting and or preparing hard copy records for scanning and document preparation.
- Followed production procedures in completing internal documentation and tracking.
- Adhered to imaging center guidelines of maintaining a clean work environment.
- Responsible for creating batches in the computer, scanning each batch, making sure the clarity of the documents is to client approval.
- Ability to work at a sustained pace to meet production rates while producing quality work.
- Possessed a strong problem solving ability, acceptable of change and long duration of project assignments.
- Ability to work independently with minimal supervision.

#### **Nyeri Water and Sanitation Company**

Nyeri, Kenya

DATA ANALYST June 2019 - December 2019

- Developed dashboards and reports using Tableau and Power BI, resulting in a 99% increase in efficiency.
- · Installing, configuring, and maintaining database management systems (DBMS) such as Oracle, MySQL, and SQL Server.
- Installed, administered and maintained MS SQL Server 2008/2012, including upgrades, security, configuration and service packs.
- Developed, documented and mantainied installation and configuration procedures on both Windows and Linux Environments.
- Build, installed and configured Red Hat Linux servers in a data center environment.
- Monitored performance and history of infastructure with tools such as CloudWatch and Datadog.
- · Scheduled and automated full/differential/transactional backups and implemented recovery strategies.
- · Created indexes (clustered and non-clustered) to speed up query performance resulting in a 99% increase in efficiency.

### Skills

- Linux administration
- Scripting (Bash, Python)
- Programming Language (Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, REST APIs, Ruby, Python(Django))
- Version Control (Git, Gitlab)
- Automation (Ansible, Puppet, Chef)
- Virtualization (VMware, KVM)
- Containerization (Docker, Kubernetes)
- Networking (TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP)
- Security (Firewalls, SSL, SSH)

## Education

### **DEKUT(Dedan Kimathi University of Technology)**

Nyeri, Kenya

B.S. IN BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

May 2015 - June 2020